unrulymedia.com 2019-06-30

# Unruly Privacy Policy

**About us**

Unruly Group Limited, and its affiliates including Unruly Media Inc, Unruly Holdings Limited, Unruly Media Limited, Unruly Media AB, Unruly Media AS, Unruly Media GmbH, Unruly Media Inc, Unruly Media KK, Unruly Media Pte Ltd, Unruly Media Pty Ltd and Unmedia Video Distribution Sdn Bhd  (referred to herein, both individually and collectively, as “Unruly,” “we,” “us,” and “our”), will collect, use, share and disclose or otherwise process your personal information in line with this Privacy Policy.

Unruly serves and distributes video and non-video content online. Our clients are mostly advertisers that ask us to display their video content through advertising units on websites that participate in our network of publisher sites. 

**Definitions**

In this Privacy Policy, we will refer generally to the video and non-video ads and other content we serve as “ **Distributed Content** ” and the sites we work with in our publisher network which offer and display our clients’ Distributed Content as “ **Participant Sites**.” This Privacy Policy will also deal with sites that are owned and operated by Unruly, such as [unruly.co](https://www.unruly.co/) and all associated subdomains and [console.unrulymedia.com](https://console.unrulymedia.com/). These sites are referred to as the “ **Unruly Sites**.”

When you use any Unruly Site or service provided by Unruly, you — as an advertiser or publisher client or other user of our sites — are accepting this Privacy Policy, and Unruly will have the right to use your information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to have your information used in any of the ways described in this Privacy Policy, you must discontinue use of the Unruly Site and any services provided by Unruly.

By using any Unruly Site, you acknowledge the transfer of your personal data to countries outside the EEA. This is explained in more detail below.

By using any Unruly Site, you are consenting to the placing of cookies and other technologies on your devices which allow Unruly to collect certain information. We provide more detail on this below.

If you have any queries about how we collect or use your personal data, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#debabfaabfaeacb1aabbbdaab7b1b09eb0bba9adf0bdb1f0abb5)

This Privacy Policy will describe the kinds of information Unruly may collect from or use or disclose about you or your computer or device when you visit an Unruly Site or when you encounter Distributed Content served by Unruly at a Participant Site. All Participant Sites are operated or controlled by third parties, and the collection, use and disclosure of information collected by a Participant Site or other parties working with such site are governed its or their privacy policies. This Privacy Policy does not apply to Participant Sites or such other parties.

### Technologies used by Unruly to collect information

Unruly reserves the right to use one or more varieties of technologies to collect information at Participant Sites and Unruly Sites. These are listed and described below.

**Pixels**. A tracking “pixel” is a transparent graphic image (usually 1 pixel x 1 pixel) that is placed on a web page and allows for the collection of information regarding the use of the web page that contains the tracking pixel. Unruly collects technical and usage information (see below) through the use of tracking pixels.

**Cookies**. A “cookie” is used by a website to send some data to a user’s device. Depending on the settings of the device or web browser this data may be stored on the user’s device so that the device can later return that data to the same website. Cookies can be used by online services, such as websites or ad technologies, to recognize an Internet- or mobile-connected device that they have encountered before. Unruly uses cookies at certain Unruly Sites to help regulate and facilitate the use by our clients of the console and other client account areas. Unruly may also set cookies, on its own behalf or for a client’s or other third party’s benefit (see below sections entitled “Clients” and “Third party suppliers or services”) to store information (on an anonymous basis) about the browsing activities of the one or more users of a connected device or its web browser(s) when displaying Distributed Content. A user may configure his or her web browsers to accept or reject or delete the cookies, or notify the user when a cookie is being set.

**Clients**. Some advertisers or other clients (and their third-party service or technology providers) may use pixels, cookies, flash cookies, web beacons and/or similar technologies which are activated when their Distributed Content is viewed by users across our network of Participant Sites or at Unruly Sites. We may request and receive aggregate, non-personal information from our clients from time to time but we do not actively seek from our clients (or their service providers) any information about any individual users.

**Third party suppliers or services**. Unruly works with third party technology or service providers, such as Amazon Web Services, who provides us with hosting, serving, general campaign or site analytics, ad serving data, or demographic and other audience data about the use and viewership of our clients’ Distributed Content, the Participant Sites we work with or our Unruly Sites. Such third party providers may utilize pixels, cookies, flash cookies, web beacons and/or similar technologies that may be activated when our clients’ Distributed Content is encountered on a Participant Site or a user arrives at an Unruly Site. Further, Unruly may work with or permit certain contracted third parties to use our video player to serve cookies, web beacons or similar technologies to collect information about you in order to serve you with targeted ads at other sites you may visit on the Internet or elsewhere, such as to re-target you (or, your browser) with display advertising that is directly relevant to a video advertisement Unruly displayed which you may have viewed. In such instances, our video player will provide links to information regarding such third parties, their privacy policies and how to “opt-out” of such third party data collection efforts.  (See below section entitled “ **Interaction with Video Player and Other Usage Information”**  and [Unruly RTB Privacy Policy](https://video.unrulymedia.com/rtbprivacypolicy/index.html)). To be clear, in all instances where the use, collection and disclosure of information is by one of these third party providers, their privacy policies shall govern and this Privacy Policy does not apply. We do not actively seek or knowingly receive information from these third party providers about individual users.

**Opt-Out**.  Unruly is a member of the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA), a cooperative of companies committed to building responsible advertising policies across the Internet, and adheres to the DAA’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. Our opt-out tool can be found [here](https://video.unrulymedia.com/rtbprivacypolicy/index.html). To learn more about interest based or online behavioral advertising, and other advertising companies’ privacy practices and opt-out from each or any of them (including Unruly), you may also go directly to the DAA website at [http://optout.aboutads.info/](http://optout.aboutads.info/).

### Information collection on Participant Sites

When you visit a participant site in our advertising network and view distributed content placed by us, we collect information about your activities as follows:

**Technical Information**. When we serve distributed content, we log and analyze technical information that is openly available to our servers such as information about the kind of browser being used (e.g., Safari, Internet Explorer), the type of operating system it’s running on (e.g., Windows, Mac OS, mobile OSes), the speed and type of Internet connection (e.g., narrowband, broadband, mobile), and other technical information. This information is anonymous and generally non-personally identifiable but does include “internet protocol addresses” or “IP addresses” which can be used to identify a user and may be considered to be “personally identifiable information” (see below). Unruly archives all technical information (including any such IP addresses) in raw log format.

**IP Addresses** : Unruly analyzes “internet protocol addresses” or “IP addresses” in order to determine an approximate geographic location so that we can serve a client’s Distributed Content that is more relevant to that location and/or perform other analyses based on information that may be collected about the history of interactions with our video player (see below) or clients’ Distributed Content that are common to any single or range of IP addresses. We may also collect or use IP address information for fraud detection or prevention. We archive IP address data as part of the raw log files of technical information maintained by our systems (see above). Unless you use a static IP address, an IP address typically relates to multiple businesses, households or larger communities. For example, if you use an Internet Service Provider (ISP) to access the Internet, your IP address may be assigned from a range of IP addresses. Unruly has no influence or control over how any IP address is assigned. An assigned IP address may also change from time to time within that range of IP addresses. While not impossible, especially if a user has been assigned an IP address permanently or for a period of time, it is difficult to identify an individual user based on an IP address and we do not actively associate IP addresses with any other information in order to identify any individual user on a personally identifiable basis.

**Advertising Campaigns**. Some Distributed Content may seek to collect personally identifiable or other information as part of a promotion or other offering by our advertising client or the Participant Site. If a user provides the requested information, Unruly may collect, store and provide such information to its client. Unruly stores this information for a period of time following the conclusion of the offering for both archival and legal reasons. The use of such information by the applicable client seeking such information will be governed by such client’s privacy policy.  

**Interaction with Video Player and Other Usage Information**. Unruly uses a proprietary video player to serve our clients’ Distributed Content. This video player can be hosted on a web page, be featured as part of an application or widget, or be embedded within an advertising unit. Unruly collects data about a user’s interactions with the player, such as what Distributed Content has been featured, played or clicked, whether playback is paused or stopped, and information collected in relation to the serving and display of Distributed Content. Additionally, we may also collect information about the pages you visited at a Participant Site if our video player or Distributed Content are present on the pages, including what site or page you came from, how long you spent on the page, your click activity on the page. The usage and interaction data helps us understand and report to our clients about whether and how often an item of Distributed Content is watched, whether partially or fully, and in what context, by users across our network of Participant Sites. It may also be used to target or re-target relevant advertising or other content to you through involvement of contracted third parties and/or on other sites you visit. Unruly may also use this information to determine what Distributed Content to show in the video player by matching usage with historical data that Unruly may have collected and stored using cookie or other technology. (See above section entitled “ **Third party suppliers or services** ”).

**Sharing and Social Media Features**. Unruly works with social media tools, services and networks, such as Facebook and Twitter. We provide users with both proprietary and branded tools to enable them to share an item of Distributed Content, solicit or refer other users to view Distributed Content, or express or broadcast their opinion about an item of Distributed Content. In some cases, the use of these tools will require a user to provide personally-identifiable information. If you use a tag, button or sharing feature that is provided by a branded third-party social media service or network, such as the Facebook’s “Like” button, you may be required to log-in to your account or otherwise take steps to access such third party services. Such collection, use and disclosure of any information by or in relation to such third party service is subject to its privacy policy, and this Privacy Policy does not apply.

**Our legal bases for using personal information**

All organisations need a legal reason to use your personal information. There are a number of legal grounds that enable data processing. Below are the most relevant grounds you should be aware of. 

**With your consent**

There are some activities where we process personal information with your consent. For example, where we want to send you marketing messages by email, we would ask your permission first and you could opt out at any time. 

**For a legitimate interest**

We may use your information where there is a legitimate interest to do so. For example, we may use your information where it would help achieve our business objectives or to facilitate a benefit to you or someone else. 

We only rely on legitimate interests if the reason for using your information is fair and lawful. Where we want to rely on legitimate interests as a legal basis, we will carry out a balancing test between our legitimate interests and your privacy rights. 

Our legitimate interests in processing personal data include:

  * to develop, deliver and maintain relevant and engaging products, services and advertising;
  * understanding when audiences engage with our clients’ ads;
  * to build a clearer understanding of who our clients’ audiences are in order to better serve more relevant advertising to those audiences, for the benefit of both individuals and our clients;
  * to maximise advertising revenues for publishers and therefore help to maintain a diverse ecosystem of online independent publishers of content for users to enjoy and educate themselves;
  * to support individual and societal rights to receive information;
  * to improve user website experience by delivering brand safe, high quality advertising to all of the publishers of online content with which we work;
  * to carry on the business of a commercial organisation;
  * to demonstrate that we provide services and products to agreed industry standards;
  * sharing information with News Corp group companies for analysis, audience insights, business efficiencies, content personalisation and to deliver relevant advertising.

**To comply with legal obligations**

There may be situations where we need to use your information to comply with legal and regulatory obligations or defend claims. 

**How Unruly uses your information**

Unruly uses the information it collects to operate and improve the functionality, presentation, distribution and appeal of the Distributed Content we place for our clients on Unruly’s network of Participant Sites. On occasion, this involves sharing log level data with a client if we ascertain that the information being shared is the same information that such advertising or publisher client was in a position to have collected themselves. We may also share aggregated audience data (built from information collected about you and other users visiting a Participant Site) with certain key clients, who will use such information in accordance with their own privacy policy and applicable laws. 

The information may also be used to improve the relevance of the Distributed Content served to you and other users visiting a Participant Site. We also use and share aggregated technical and usage data with our publishers and advertisers in order to provide measurement and analytics on the effectiveness of their ad campaigns and content distribution programs, and to conduct research and analysis, including to test different ways, to improve the experience of users who encounter our clients’ Distributed Content on our network of Participant Sites. We may use the information collected from a particular browser or device, or transfer such information to a third party, for the purposes of cross-device mapping or matching. Cross-device mapping or matching means the practice of linking two or more devices or browsers used or likely used (based on analysis) by the same user for online behavioural advertising purposes.

Unruly is part of the News Corporation (“News Corp”) group of companies, and as such, we may rely on our legitimate interests as an organisation that facilitates more relevant advertising for the benefit of our advertiser clients and publisher partners, to share your information with News Corp and its affiliates to: 

  * perform analytics and analysis of how you interact with the News Corp group’s products and services, to facilitate business efficiencies and develop products and services that would be relevant to you; and 
  * deliver more relevant advertising from across our News Corp network. 

If you would like to opt out of this sharing or exercise your data protection rights, you can email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) but please bear in mind that opting out will relate to any future sharing and not to information already shared. For more information about how to exercise your rights, please see the section on Access and control of your personal information. Opting out may also mean you do not receive the best experience across News Corp products, services and websites.

Where your information is used for advertising purposes, you will be provided with information about how it is used and be able to control what information is used and how, as well as with which affiliates it is shared.  
These affiliates may be located inside or outside of the EEA, including the United States of America. We have appropriate agreements in place to ensure they protect your information in accordance with our legal obligations.  
We also participate in an advertising platform offered by our affiliate, NC Audience Exchange LLC, called News IQ. To learn more about News Corp Connect please visit <http://ncaudienceexchange.com/about/>.

Unruly may disclose one or more clients’ and/or individual users’ information if required to do so by law (or in a good faith belief that such action is necessary or advisable in order to comply with any laws of any country or region which may assert jurisdiction) or in order to respond to a judicial or other governmental action, order, subpoena, request, demand or warrant. We may make such disclosures without providing notice to you.

Unruly also reserves the right to disclose one or more clients’ and/or individual users’ information if it is appropriate or necessary in Unruly’s discretion in order to: take precautions against liability; protect against fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses; investigate or defend against any third-party actions or allegations (including assisting a client or third party to do so); assist government enforcement agencies; or protect the security, integrity, rights, property, or personal safety of Unruly, its systems and services, as well as its employees, clients or others. 

Unruly may in the future, and shall have the right to implement technology to, collect or share any information, including any client’s or individual user’s information, that we determine to be necessary or advisable in order to comply with a judicial order or to cooperate with government and law enforcement officials.

If Unruly sells all, or parts of the company or its affiliates, your information may be one of the transferred business assets. If this happens, your information may be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s advisers and will be passed on to the new owners of the business for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy and to ensure continuity of your selected services. 

### Personal data collection on Unruly Sites

Personal data is collected on the Unruly Sites in various instances including, without limitation:

**Registration and Use of Unruly’s Services**. If you register to participate in the Unruly network as a publisher or an advertiser, we will require you to provide, and we will store, information that identifies you personally such as your name, contact information, and payment method. We use this information for business purposes such as account maintenance, billing, and to operate and provide the Unruly services.

**Requested information**. If you submit an inquiry to or respond to a request by Unruly through any “Contact Us form” or similar function on an Unruly Site, any information you provide, including any contact name, address, email address, telephone number, financial information, etc., will be used by Unruly in order to respond to such inquiry or request.

**Subscriptions**. You may provide an email address or other contact information or otherwise interact with our Unruly Sites in order to commence receiving a subscription-based function or service, such as a newsletter or mailing.

**Social media, etc**. You may provide an email address or other unique identifier or be requested to provide login information in order to use a social media or sharing feature. Where the feature is branded according to a branded social network or social media service, Unruly does not have visibility or access to such login or other identifier you use, and you will be bound by the privacy policy of the relevant social network.

**Access to web-based client interface or console**. A current client in good standing may be required to provide his or her username and password, which may include or feature personally-identifiable information, in order to access the UnrulyX console, account areas and/or other areas that are accessible only by clients. We use user IDs and passwords, in part, to protect your privacy and security. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information at all times.

You may, of course, decline to share any or certain items of personally-identifiable information with Unruly, in which case we may be unable to provide you with the services or pay you any monies that might otherwise be payable to you. Unruly archives any and all information, including personally identifiable information, that may be input in any registration process even if the user refuses or is declined or fails to use or abandons the services provided by Unruly.

**Note about Children’s Privacy** : Unruly is very sensitive to the issue of children’s privacy. Our websites, products, and services are neither developed for, nor directed at, children, and we do not knowingly collect personal information about children under 13. If you believe your child has provided Unruly with personally identifiable data by registering or using any offerings at any of our Unruly Sites (i.e., sites owned and operated by Unruly, as opposed to a Participant Site over which we have no control), and you would like to have us look into removing the data from our servers, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#731712071203011c071610071a1c1d331d1604005d101c5d0618)

### Where Unruly stores Personal Data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfillment of your order or the provision of support services. However, we only transfer your information where there are appropriate measures and controls in place and all information you provide to us is stored on secure servers.

### Use of information that clients provide

Unruly uses the personal data you provide to respond to your enquiries and requests, and to keep accurate records concerning the services you are requesting through any Unruly Site. We generally use non-personally identifiable information in aggregated form to help measure the performance and effectiveness of our Unruly Sites, and to improve their usefulness. Additionally, you should be aware of the following:

  * Unruly does not share personally identifiable information of any clients with other organizations for their marketing or promotional uses without your express consent. 
  * To provide web site hosting, maintenance and security, fulfill orders, offer certain functionality, improve our site, and create new site features, we may disclose one or more clients’ information to affiliated companies or other businesses or persons, such as, for example, credit card service providers or cloud or data storage providers. 
  * Any personally identifiable information a client provides may be associated with technical and usage information that may be collected at Unruly Sites in same manner as we may collect such information at Participant Sites (see above). 
  * We may also combine it with information collected from other sources, particularly in cases where we and our third party partners or contractors may be vetting or investigating a new, existing or prospective client for potential of fraud or other undesirable activities.

### Access and control of your information

Where we rely on your consent to process personal information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. Please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#325653465342405d465751465b5d5c725c5745411c515d1c4759) with details of your request. In some instances we may still have an alternative legal basis to continue to process that personal information and we will inform you of that. If you do withdraw consent we may not be able to provide the product or service you have requested. 

If you have a comment, concern or suggestion, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#a4c0c5d0c5d4d6cbd0c1c7d0cdcbcae4cac1d3d78ac7cb8ad1cf). If you have a complaint and we cannot resolve the matter, you have the right to comply to the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/) or the data protection regulator responsible for your country or region. 

### Retention of personal data

We will retain your information for as long as necessary for the uses set out in this Privacy Policy, or while there is a legitimate reason for doing so. If you ask us to delete your information before that time, we may not be able to do so due to technical, legal, regulatory or contractual constraints. For example, we would need to retain your name and contact details for suppression purposes if you do not want to receive direct marketing from us. 

### Changes to this Policy

Unruly may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. This may be in relation to changes in the law, best practice, changes in our services or treatment of personal information. Where necessary, we will seek your consent to these changes. We will always display clearly when this Privacy Policy was last amended.

### Contact us

In addition to any general data protection enquiries you may have, you can use the below details to contact our Group Data Protection Officer:

By email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#583c392c39282a372c3d3b2c31373618363d2f2b763b37762d33)

By mail: Unruly Group Limited, The White Chapel Building, 15 Whitechapel High Street, London, E1 8QS

Last updated: June 2018
